<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mobile Social Networks | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/mobile-social-networks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-06T14:43:33+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opera releases "State of the Mobile Web"]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/opera-releases-state-of-the-mobile-web_171.html"/>
    <updated>2008-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/opera-releases-state-of-the-mobile-web_171</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Opera released its interesting and insightful <a href="http://www.opera.com/mobile_report"><strong>&ldquo;State of the Mobile Web&rdquo; report</strong></a>. In this report, Opera analyzed the traffic of more than 44 million cumulative Opera Mini users worldwide.<br>
<strong>Opera Mini: the world&rsquo;s most popular mobile browser</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Since its worldwide launch in 2006, Opera Mini has become the world&rsquo;s most popular mobile web browser with millions of users and billions of page views:<br>
<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_users.jpg" title="operamini_users.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_users.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_users.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_pages.jpg" title="operamini_pages.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_pages.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_pages.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_data.jpg" title="operamini_data.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_data.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_data.jpg" /></a><br>
<strong>Social Networking Services drive mobile web usage worldwide</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Interestingly, almost 40% of all visited web pages with Opera Mini were social networking services. In the US, South Africa and Indonesia even more than 60% of the user were visiting these services with their mobile devices. That shows social networking services are very popular worldwide.<br>
<strong>Top 10 Sites in the US, India, South Africa, UK and Germany</strong><br>
<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_us.jpg" title="operamini_us.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_us.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_us.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_india.jpg" title="operamini_india.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_india.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_india.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_sa.jpg" title="operamini_sa.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_sa.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_sa.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_uk.jpg" title="operamini_uk.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_uk.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_uk.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_germany.jpg" title="operamini_germany.jpg"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/operamini_germany.thumbnail.jpg" alt="operamini_germany.jpg" /></a><br></p>

<br>


<p>You can find more information and the whole report here: <a href="http://www.opera.com/mobile_report"><a href="http://www.opera.com/mobile_report">http://www.opera.com/mobile_report</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interesting (Mobile) News]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/interesting-mobile-news_161.html"/>
    <updated>2008-02-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/interesting-mobile-news_161</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&ndash; <a href="http://www.youtube.com">YouTube</a></strong> revised their mobile website <a href="http://m.youtube.com">m.youtube.com</a>. Now, there is a wider range of videos available (millions of videos). You can also access your YouTube account, your Favorites, your own uploaded videos, your favorite Channels via your mobile phone, and you can share, rate or comment other user ´s clips. Uploaded videos (from your mobile phone via email/mms) will appear on <a href="http://m.youtube.com">m.youtube.com</a> as well as on <a href="http://www.youtube.com.">www.youtube.com.</a><br>
Last but not least, YouTube for Mobile went international. It is also now available for the UK, Italy, France, Spain, Netherlands, Poland, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, Australia, Hong Kong, Taiwan, New Zealand, Germany, and Russia.<br>
For more info (including a video) check out: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/blog?entry=sAyN42I_HMI">YouTube Blog</a><br>
&ndash; The German student social network <a href="http://www.studivz.net"><strong>StudiVZ</strong></a> prepares itself against the market entry of his US competitor <a href="http://www.facebook.com">Facebook</a>. StudiVZ plans to provide APIs for developers. They are also thinking about joining <a href="http://code.google.com/apis/opensocial/">Google&rsquo;s initiative OpenSocial</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mig33.com"><strong>Mig33</strong></a> announced closing a Series B funding of $13.5 million led by DCM with participation from existing Series A investors Accel, Redpoint and TVP. Mig33 is a downloadable mobile social networking application. They currently have over 9 million users across more than 200 countries. Mig33 will use the money to continue expansion of the company in the U.S. and internationally.<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li>The mobile social network <a href="http://www.mocospace.com"><strong>MocoSpace</strong></a> has raised $4 million in its second round of funding, drawing from existing investors General Catalyst, Bob Pittman&rsquo;s Pilot Group and former eBay exec Michael Dearing reports <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/01/27/mocospace-raises-4-million-b-round/">TechCrunch</a>. The Boston-based company already raised $3 million in the first round in January 2007. MocoSpace has 2 million members and 1 billion pageviews/month from mobile phones.<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.motorola.com/mediacenter/news/detail.jsp?globalObjectId=9233_9162_23"><strong>Motorola</strong></a> considers an elimination of his weak mobile devices department. The goal would be to regain lost market shares. But the consideration is not final. Greg Brown, President and Chief Executive Officer: &ldquo;We are exploring ways in which our Mobile Devices Business can accelerate its recovery and retain and attract talent while enabling our shareholders to realize the value of this great franchise.&rdquo;<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.opera.com">Opera</a> announced the commercial release of the latest mobile Web browser <strong>Opera Mobile 9.5</strong> at the <a href="http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/homepage.htm">Mobile World Congress</a> (MWC, once 3GSM) in Barcelona. &ldquo;the Opera Mobile 9.5 desktop-like browsing experience has been enhanced with innovations such as zooming and panning that make it easier to navigate, load pages quicker and get users closer to the Web content and entertainment they want. With Opera Mobile 9.5, users can experience the real Web and interact with content exactly as they do on their PC.&rdquo; (Source: <a href="http://www.opera.com/pressreleases/en/2008/02/05/"><a href="http://www.opera.com/pressreleases">http://www.opera.com/pressreleases</a></a>).<br>
Watch the Opera Mobile 9.5 Guided Tour (video) <a href="http://www.opera.com/b2b/solutions/mobile/video/">here</a>.<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li>At the <a href="http://www.mobileworldcongress.com/homepage.htm">Mobile World Congress 2008 in Barcelona</a> <strong>Microsoft</strong> will unveil <strong>version 6.1 of its Windows Mobile OS</strong>. Amongst a new application (&ldquo;One Note Mobile&rdquo;) there are an improved Internet Explorer as well as a Chat view for text messages. One Note Mobile includes voice messages, notepad and drawings. Find more info here: <a href="http://www.golem.de/0802/57444.html">golem.de</a> and <a href="http://msmobiles.com/news.php/7065.html">msmobiles.com</a><br>
<strong>Sources:</strong><br>
StudiVZ: <a href="http://www.golem.de/0801/57279.html">golem.de</a><br>
Mig33: <a href="http://www.themobiblog.com/2008/01/aussie-mobile-social-network-targets.html">themobiblog.com</a>, <a href="http://www.personalbee.com/261/27179903">personalbee.com</a><br>
MocoSpace: <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/01/27/mocospace-raises-4-million-b-round/">techcrunch.com</a>Motorola: <a href="http://www.motorola.com/mediacenter/news/detail.jsp?globalObjectId=9233_9162_23">motorola.com</a>, <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/01/27/mocospace-raises-4-million-b-round/"></a><a href="http://www.heise.de/newsticker/meldung/102839/from/rss09">heise.de</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huge deal between Nokia and Facebook?]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/huge-deal-between-nokia-and-facebook_158.html"/>
    <updated>2008-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/huge-deal-between-nokia-and-facebook_158</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>According to <a href="http://www.paidcontent.org/entry/419-nokia-and-facebook-working-on-mobile-deal-could-involve-investment/">paidcontent.org</a> Nokia is in talks with Facebook about a potential partnership and investment. </strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Nokia and Facebook are in negotiations about porting Facebook on the home screen of several Nokia handsets. This deal could be huge, since Nokia is the world&rsquo;s largest maker of mobile phones. Nokia already tartgeted some mobile services for their devices:<ul> <li>Ovi (mobile web service)</li>   <li>Mosh (mobile social network)</li>   <li>Navteq (location based services)</li>   <li>Universal (music)</li>  <li>Avvenu (file sharing)</li>  <li>Twango (media sharing)</li> <li>Enpocket (mobile advertising)</li></ul><br>
This deal could help Facebook expand in the European market. Nokia is also looking into purchasing a stake of Facebook.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Talks are still very early. A senior Nokia executive declined to go into details: &ldquo;There is talk of a partnership in the works it&rsquo;s safe to say we&rsquo;re testing the waters and things still have to be worked out.&rdquo;<br></p>

<br>


<p>So no specific details have been released yet, but maybe <a href="http://www.mobilemag.com/content/100/340/C14366">mobilemag.com</a> is right with &ldquo;The giant just got bigger&rdquo;.<strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Sources:</strong><a href="http://www.mobilemag.com/content/100/340/C14366"><br>
mobilemag.com</a><a href="http://www.paidcontent.org/entry/419-nokia-and-facebook-working-on-mobile-deal-could-involve-investment/">paidcontent.org</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SD Forum 09/06/2007]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/sd-forum-06092007_134.html"/>
    <updated>2007-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/sd-forum-06092007_134</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday there was <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-internet-sig-mobile-user-experience_117.html">another Mobile Internet SIG event</a> organized by <a href="http://www.sdforum.com">SD Forum</a>. This month&rsquo;s topic was <span class="appTitle1"><a href="http://www.sdforum.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=Calendar.eventDetail&amp;eventID=12919">Social Networking &amp; Mobile Phone Services</a>.  </span><br></p>

<br>


<p>The first presentation was held by Steve Granek from <a href="http://www.neustar.biz/">NeuStar, Inc</a>. Not only is Steve a great speaker, but he&rsquo;s also very knowledgeable in what he was talking about: problems with multi-service providing for carriers and network operators. It comes down to the fact that mobile phones (and networks) have originally been created to provide voice service, not data services such as SMS, MMS or web access. The biggest issues with this is address routing and interoperability. We heard in-depth facts about how routing a regular phone call is different from getting the route to someone who is supposed to receive a text message (that&rsquo;s the address part). Interoperability is a big issue, because carriers tend to approach widespread problems with their own focus only, so e.g. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_Multimedia_Subsystem">IMS</a> was mentioned as a great thing with the exact same problem.<br></p>

<!--more-->


<p>One very interesting, even though a bit frightening sentence in Steve&rsquo;s presentation was that convergence is happening (mobile+web) in the US right now and that it will be running the carriers over like a bus&hellip;there&rsquo;s an image.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The second presentation came from John Kesler, CEO of <a href="http://fonherd.com">Fonherd</a>. <span class="appOutput">Fonherd, a startup based in Los Angeles, is &ldquo;a mobile social networking platform utilizing permission-based mobile phone directories to provide content, commerce and communication to existing and emergent communities&rdquo; (quoted from </span><a href="http://www.sdforum.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=Calendar.eventDetail&amp;eventID=12919"><a href="http://www.sdforum.com">http://www.sdforum.com</a></a>)<span class="appOutput">. They are going to launch their service in about four weeks in the UK, and after that in the United States. The whole thing is mostly SMS based and they are planning to make money from the commerce part of the application. That is via coupons someone gets via SMS when he/she joins the herd of a company giving them out. It reminded me a little bit of <a href="http://www.zyb.com">zyb</a>, also a social network that is based on directories of numbers, in the case of zyb however, these numbers are synced from the phone to the web (that&rsquo;s how it all started).</span><br></p>

<br>


<p>Nice event!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Social Networks Are Growing]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-social-networks-are-growing_124.html"/>
    <updated>2007-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-social-networks-are-growing_124</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> I found an very interesting article about mobile social networks <a href="http://mashable.com/2007/08/15/mobile-sns-grow-worldwide/">on mashable.com</a>. It is about a report of M:Metrics, which indicates that mobile social networks are growing worldwide and that they actually can be seen as a driver for mobile web usage in Europe as well as in the US.<br>
<strong>By the numbers:</strong><br>
M:Metrics is reporting that in June 12.3 million consumers were accessing a social network via their mobile phones in the US and Western Europe. The US had the largest number of users (7.5 million mobile subscribers), followed by Italy (1.3 million), then the UK (1.1 million) and then Spain, Germany and France.<br>
<strong>The most visited mobile social networks:</strong><br>
In June the most visited mobile social networks in the US and the UK were:<br>
&ndash; MySpace (3.7 million mobile users in the US and 440,000 in the UK)<br>
&ndash; Facebook (2 million mobile users in the US and 307,000 in the UK)<br>
&ndash; Bebo (288,000 mobile users in the UK)<br>
&ndash; YouTube (901,000 mobile visits in the US)<br></p>

<br>


<p>In France, Germany, Italy and Spain the most popular mobile social network was <a href="http://home.services.spaces.live.com/">MSN&rsquo;s Live Spaces</a>, which is only available off-portal. That means  users were accessing this service through their mobile web browser and not through their operator&rsquo;s site.<br></p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>Which services were used the most by which operators?</strong><br>
Helio and Nextel     &ndash;&gt; MySpace<br>
Virgin, Sprint         &ndash;&gt; Facebook<br>
Amp&rsquo;d, AT&amp;T         &ndash;&gt; MySpace and Facebook<br>
Verizon         &ndash;&gt; YouTube<br></p>

<br>


<p>These are quite interesting facts and it shows a strong correlation between popularity and being on-portal. Those network operators were pushing these services to their users.<br>
<strong>And here&rsquo;s some more stats about mobile subscriber monthly consumption of content and applications in the US and the UK:</strong><br>
<img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/mmetrics-1.png" alt="mmetrics-1.png" /><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/mmetrics-2.png" alt="mmetrics-2.png" /><br></p>

<br>


<p>What do you think about mobile social networks &ndash; on the mobile web or as applications, on- or off-portal? Are you using them &ndash; which one(s)?<br></p>

<br>


<p>Source: <a href="http://mashable.com/2007/08/15/mobile-sns-grow-worldwide/">mashable.com</a>, <a href="http://www.moconews.net/entry/419-myspace-leads-mobile-social-network-use-in-us-uk-msns-live-spaces-prefe/">moconews.net</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
