<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: en | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-06T14:25:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PavingWays Limited]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Launches Volume Purchasing for Business Customers]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/apple-launches-volume-purchasing-for-business-customers_2396.html"/>
    <updated>2011-07-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/apple-launches-volume-purchasing-for-business-customers_2396</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/business/vpp/">Apple has announced</a> that it allows businesses to purchase apps in volume. With the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/appstore/resources/volume/">Volume Purchase Program</a> the buyer can choose an app, determine the needed quantity and complete the purchase with the corporate credit card. The buyer then receives redemption codes which he can send out.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The Volume Purchase Program is only available in the US. Every paid app in the App Store is available for businesses to buy in volume. Free apps are excluded.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Businesses need first to <a href="http://images.apple.com/business/docs/ASVPP_Business_Guide_US.pdf">create a volume purchasing account</a>. Once enrolled, they can purchase apps on the program&rsquo;s website &ndash; they aren&rsquo;t using the App Store in iTunes.<h3>Custom B2B Apps</h3><br>
The Volume Purchase Program also provides businesses the opportunity to purchase custom B2B apps built by third-party developers. These apps have been developed in collaboration with third-party developers to address a unique business need. Therefore they are not available to the general public for purchase. The minimum price for a custom B2B app is $9.99.<h3>What we think</h3><br>
It is interesting to see that Apple is now courting enterprises with this B2B App Store. Apple has recognized that employees are using iPhones and iPads also at work. It is much more easier now for businesses to distribute custom apps within their company or to specific partners. Companies are more flexible now to create and distribute apps for enterprise customers that have custom data and process needs.<br>
<strong>More info:</strong><a href="http://www.apple.com/business/vpp/">apple.com</a><a href="http://images.apple.com/business/docs/ASVPP_Business_Guide_US.pdf">Volume Purchase Program &ndash; Guide (PDF)</a><a href="https://developer.apple.com/appstore/resources/volume/">Volume Purchase Program &ndash; FAQ</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[QR-Codes As Marketing Tool]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/qr-codes-as-marketing-tool_2323.html"/>
    <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/qr-codes-as-marketing-tool_2323</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across an interesting report from <a href="http://www.i-nigma.com/pr26.html">3GVision</a>, the creator of the <a href="http://www.i-nigma.com/i-nigmahp.html">i-nigma barcode scanner</a>. The numbers show a worldwide growth in mobile barcode usage. The US is leading the growth, but the popularity of barcodes is also increasing in Europe with Germany, the UK and Italy leading this trend. So maybe this is finally catching up outside of Japan?<br>
<strong>Top 10 users of mobile barcodes during May 2011:</strong><p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1)   1. United States<br>
(2)   2. Germany<br>
(4)   3. United Kingdom<br>
(3)   4. Italy<br>
(5)   5. Canada<br>
(6)   6. Netherlands<br>
(7)   7. France<br>
(8)   8. Hong Kong<br>
(9)   9. Spain<br>
(13) 10. Australia</p><p style="padding-left: 30px;">Position in () was in April/2011</p><strong>Top 5 growing countries for May 2011:</strong><p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Australia (74.1% Growth over April/2011)<br>
2. Hong Kong (43.3%)<br>
3. United States (39.0%)<br>
4. France (32.2%)<br>
5. United Kingdom (31.5%)</p><strong>Global growth in mobile barcode usage Q4/09–Q1/11:</strong><p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/chart.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2325" title="chart" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/chart-300x264.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="264" /></a></p><br>
* see below for notes on reporting methodology<h3>QR-Codes and Marketing</h3><br>
As mentioned in the report the mobile barcode usage is increasing in Germany. On <a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwelt.com/2011/06/30/top-5-mobile-marketing-kampagnen-juni-2011/">mobilemarketingwelt.com</a> I found some interesting mobile marketing campaigns using QR codes (&ldquo;Quick Response Codes&rdquo;). Here are some examples how companies already using QR-Codes in their advertisment.<br>
<strong>1. Bausch + Lomb &ndash; QR-Code, SMS, Mobile Couponing</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>The pharmaceutical company Bausch+Lomb uses QR-Codes and SMS shortcode in his <a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwelt.com/2011/06/24/bauschlomb-nutzt-mobile-couponing/">print ads</a>. By scanning the QR code the user will be forwarded to a mobile landing page where he receives more information about Biotrue, a care product for contact lenses. He also gets a coupon there for a free product sample.<br>
In case the user has no QR-Code reader on his mobile phone he can request a link to the mobile portal via SMS shortcode.<br>
<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Bausch+Lomb_QR-Code.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2340" title="Bausch+Lomb_QR-Code" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Bausch+Lomb_QR-Code-82x300.jpg" alt="" width="82" height="300" /></a><br>
<strong>2. Globetrotter – QR-Codes</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>The equipment manufacturer Globetrotter used QR-Codes <a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwelt.com/2011/06/06/globetrotter-setzt-auf-qr-codes-2/">in his latest print campaign</a>. By scanning the QR code on the advertisement the user will get to a mobile landing page where he receives more information about the reforestation project &ldquo;Globetrotter VisionsWald&rdquo;.<br>
<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Globetrotter_QR-Code4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2337" title="Globetrotter_QR-Code4" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Globetrotter_QR-Code4-218x300.jpg" alt="" width="218" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Globetrotter_Mobile-Portal.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2338" title="Globetrotter_Mobile-Portal" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/Globetrotter_Mobile-Portal-250x300.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /></a><br>
<strong>3. Universal Music – image recognition</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>In his latest <a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwelt.com/2011/06/22/universal-music-bewirbt-lady-gaga-album-mit-u-snap-plakatkampagne/">poster advertising campaign</a> for the new Lady Gaga Album Universal Music uses the <a href="http://www.wall.de/en/press/news/walldecaux_launcht_u_snap_in_deutschland">U snap App from Wall AG</a>, a value-added app for smartphones, on the German market. The user has to download the free U snap App for iPhone or Android smartphones from the App Store. When starting the app the user can take a picture of the print ad and gets samples from the new Lady Gaga album, can view music videos or win concert tickets, fan packages and CDs.<br>
About 15,000 City Light Posters with the slogan &ldquo;Fly to Lady Gaga with U snap&rdquo; accompany the release of the new album &ldquo;Born This Way&rdquo;.<br>
<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/U-snap_Lady-Gaga.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2358" title="U-snap_Lady-Gaga" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/U-snap_Lady-Gaga-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><h3>Our Opinion:</h3><br>
Many brands and retailers already started using QR-Codes in their marketing campaigns. For example <a href="http://mobile-tagging.blogspot.com/2011/07/mein-burger-von-mcdonalds-mit-qr-codes.html">McDonalds</a>, <a href="http://mobile-tagging.blogspot.com/2011/03/vichy-mit-qr-code-branding.html">Vichy</a>, <a href="http://mobile-tagging.blogspot.com/2011/02/extended-packaging-frischfleisch-bei.html">Aldi Süd</a>, <a href="http://www.tagmotion.de/2011/06/28/qr-code-supermarkt/">Tesco</a> etc. The biggest advantage of QR-Codes is that customers get further information about a product fast and easy. They just need a mobile phone with a camera, web access and a QR-Code reader software (e.g. <a href="http://reader.kaywa.com/">Kaywa Reader</a>, <a href="http://www.quickmark.com.tw/En/basic/download.asp">QuickMark Barcode Reader</a>, <a href="http://www.i-nigma.com/Downloadi-nigmaReader.html">i-nigma Reader</a>).<br></p>

<br>


<p>There are various opportunities of using QR-Codes. Companies can use them as a direct response marketing tool for print campaigns (call-to-action) or even to sell virtual goods like games, music or ringtones. I think the usage of QR Codes will be increasing in the future and we will see a wide range of usage of QR-Codes in marketing.<br>
<strong>Sources:</strong><a href="http://www.i-nigma.com/pr26.html">i-nigma</a><a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwelt.com/2011/06/30/top-5-mobile-marketing-kampagnen-juni-2011/">mobilemarketingwelt.com</a><a href="http://www.wall.de/en/press/news/walldecaux_launcht_u_snap_in_deutschland">U snap Wall AG</a><br>
<strong>* Notes on reporting methodology:</strong><ul>  <li>These reports are based on the total number of QRcode, Datamatrix and UPC/EAN scans recorded by the i-nigma system during the relevant periods. Because of i‑nigma’s prominence in many markets worldwide, 3GVision believes that these numbers are likely to be indicative of global mobile barcode activity.</li> <li>The reports do not include activity in Japan, which is known to be well ahead in popularity and usage of mobile barcodes.</li>  <li>For better representation of global open market trends, the reports specifically exclude the activity of i‑nigma-based solutions that are used by our vertical customers.</li>    <li>Top 5 growing countries are from the top 20 countries in mobile barcodes usage during May/2011.</li></ul><br>
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
