<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reviews | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T22:18:37+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands-On Nokia WRT Development with Aptana]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/nokia-wrt-development-aptana-plugin_688.html"/>
    <updated>2009-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/nokia-wrt-development-aptana-plugin_688</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in April we were invited to participate in the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/nokia-developer-summit-2009-wrap-up-day-1_517.html">Nokia WRT Widget Hackathon in Monaco</a>. The event took place during the <a href="http://events.nokia.com/developersummit/">Nokia Developer Summit</a> and it was all about hacking a WRT widget together within 24 hours. 12 teams from around the world implemented widget ideas nominated in beforehand by the Nokia community. We chose to work on the travel planner idea because it relates pretty well to one of our upcoming services called <a href="http://pandaroute.com/">Panda Route &ndash; a travel diary service</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<p>With this article I want to provide some basic insights on Nokia WRT widgets, how they work and how to implement and deploy them to handsets.<br></p>

<br>


<p>WRT stands for <a href="http://www.forum.nokia.com/Technology_Topics/Web_Technologies/Web_Runtime/">Web runtime</a> and it enables you to create small applications, namely widgets, entirely built on HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Widgets are packaged and then deployed and installed on the device alongside native applications where the run in a chrome-less web browser, the web runtime environment.<!--more--><br></p>

<br>


<p>The most basic widget consists of not more than a HTML file and a widget description file that defines some settings for the runtime and tells it where the widget&rsquo;s entry point is. Of course you would normally add images, a CSS file and some JavaScript that handles all the logic and enables you to access device specific capabilities, such as calendar entries or the messaging application. Nokia offers a WRT JavaScript library to render message boxes and buttons, we used <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a> for our widget, so this is definitely possible too.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Widget files are then packaged into a .wgz file which really is just a renamed ZIP file. If you then send this .wgz file to a compatible device, it will detect that this is a widget and ask you to install it as an application.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The basic work flow to develop such a widget would be like this:<ol>    <li>write HTML/CSS/JavaScript in an editor, add images</li> <li>create the XML widget description file, namely Info.plist</li>  <li>test your widget in a web browser</li>  <li>ZIP it all into a package and rename it to .wgz</li>    <li>send it to the device via bluetooth or upload it to a web server and download it via the device&rsquo;s web browser</li>  <li>now your widget installs in the device&rsquo;s applications menu and can be used</li></ol><br>
While this is feasible you might have noticed that this work flow has its flaws, especially when it comes to testing and deploying your widget.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Therefore we were happy that Nokia joined forces with <a href="http://aptana.com/">Aptana</a> and created a <a href="http://aptana.com/nokia">WRT plugin for Aptana Studio</a> that helps you to speed up this work flow and actually enables you to write and deploy a widget in such a short time that on-device testing becomes possible.<br>
Additional to code completion, syntax highlighting and all the other nice features Aptana Studio has to offer, you can very easily create, preview, package and even deploy your widget right out of the IDE to your device.<br></p>

<br>


<p>We were using the windows version of Aptana Studio during the hackathon, but are usually working on Macs &ndash; it works there just as easily: You can switch to the preview pane while editing the widget&rsquo;s HTML file and choose from a collection of compatible Nokia phones defined by screen sizes. This gives you a more or less rough idea how the widget will look like on the device. Then you can right-click on the widget project and choose to package the whole thing into a .wgz file. Another right-click option is to deploy the widget to a device via bluetooth. This is the best feature because you can directly test your work on a real device this way. You can also deploy to Nokia&rsquo;s device emulator which however only runs on windows.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Bottom line is if you have some experience with web development and want to get into developing widgets for Nokia, we can only recommend to <a href="http://www.forum.nokia.com/Technology_Topics/Web_Technologies/Web_Runtime/QuickStart.xhtml">read some documentation</a>, get <a href="http://aptana.com/">Aptana Studio</a> and the <a href="http://aptana.com/nokia">WRT plugin</a> and get going in no time. Oh and don&rsquo;t forget to publish your widget on <a href="https://store.ovi.com/">Nokia&rsquo;s brand new OVI store</a> to make it accessible to millions of users and maybe even make a buck or two by selling it there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mobile Web Design by Cameron Moll]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/book-mobile-web-design-by-cameron-moll_136.html"/>
    <updated>2007-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/book-mobile-web-design-by-cameron-moll_136</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a HREF="http://www.mobilewebbook.com/"><img SRC="http://www.mobilewebbook.com/images/snaps/1.jpg" ALT="image of book cover" STYLE="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right" /></a>I met <a HREF="http://www.cameronmoll.com/">Cameron</a> after his first conference talk in Europe at the <a HREF="http://www.vivabit.com/atmedia2006/">@media conference</a> in London in June 2006. He was talking about the same thing there &ndash; Mobile Web Design &ndash; and I really liked his presentation. Since then we both kept on doing research in the mobile area and Cameron just released his first book and it&rsquo;s a great one!<br></p>

<br>


<p>Early chapters entitled &ldquo;Mobile Web Fundamentals&rdquo; give a great amount of background information on the mobile web market and usage, the concept of being &ldquo;mobile&rdquo; (it&rsquo;s not the device, but the user that&rsquo;s mobile) and on the fundamental limitations in this area (screen size, input methods, carriers etc.).<br></p>

<br>


<p>I especially liked the focus on what I really feel is important about the mobile web, even though it is in contrast to the newest developments in the browser and handset market: it&rsquo;s not about bringing the desktop web to mobile devices, people, it&rsquo;s about creating mobile web applications that serve people&rsquo;s needs while they&rsquo;re on the go!<br></p>

<br>


<p>Browser differences are also thoroughly covered in Cameron&rsquo;s book and even <a HREF="http://microformats.org/">Microformats</a> are mentioned as a possible way to solve context-related problems in browsers, i.e. adding contextual info to things like contacts and phone numbers in the markup, so the device knows what do do with this type of content (add it to the address book/call the number).<br></p>

<br>


<p>The main section is divided into four approaches how to implement mobile web sites  and applications: do nothing, reduce images and styling, use handheld stylesheet, create mobile-optimized content. It also covers topics like testing and validation as well as advanced techniques, such as SVG and Ajax (I&rsquo;m mentioned in a book, yeehaa!). The final chapters contain things like promoting your mobile content, dotmobi and semacodes.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Overall the book is an excellent summary of the current status in mobile web design and a great resource for anybody who thinks of creating a mobile version of his existing website or better yet, a new, web based, mobile service (that should actually be almost everybody in the web design/development community).<br></p>

<br>


<p>The book is a must-buy and it is available as a PDF at the book&rsquo;s homepage: <a HREF="http://www.mobilewebbook.com/"><a href="http://www.mobilewebbook.com">http://www.mobilewebbook.com</a></a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: "Bulletproof Ajax" by Jeremy Keith]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/book-bulletproof-ajax-by-jeremy-keith_135.html"/>
    <updated>2007-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/book-bulletproof-ajax-by-jeremy-keith_135</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bulletproofajax.com/"><img src="http://www.bulletproofajax.com/images/cover_small.gif" alt="image of book cover" style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right" /></a>I want to recommend a book by <a href="http://adactio.com/">Jeremy Keith</a>, called &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321472667/wohnflydasreg-21/">Bulletproof Ajax</a>&rdquo;. I recommend it for several reasons. First of all, the book is an excellent introduction to Ajax programming in general and everybody starting to write JavaScript code to do Ajax should read it before touching any of the libraries out there.<br>
Secondly the book is especially suited to anybody who is interested in writing Ajax powered apps on mobile devices and constrained browsers. After all the book is all about making JavaScript code bulletproof and that&rsquo;s exactly what you need to do if you are facing browser constraints, flaky implementations of JavaScript engines and a hugely fragment environment overall.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Jeremy&rsquo;s book is suited for the beginner, but also for the seasoned developer, since it makes it clear what it all comes down to: writing clean code that gracefully degrades (Jeremy calls his method to do this <a href="http://domscripting.com/blog/display/41">Hijax</a>) if the application runs in a less-than-ideal environment. There are many best practices and useful code snippets contained and topics such as JSON, web services and accessibility.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The book is not entirely new but nevertheless a must-buy, it was published New Riders Press in February 2007 and I urge everybody interested in Ajax to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321472667/wohnflydasreg-21/">grab a copy, e.g. at Amazon</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webmontag, Munich 02/12/2007]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/webmontag-munich-02122007_74.html"/>
    <updated>2007-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/webmontag-munich-02122007_74</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img id="image75" alt="webmontag_logo.jpg" style="float: right; width: 150px; margin-left: 5px" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/webmontag_logo.jpg" />A week after our visit to <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-monday-munich-02052007_72.html">Mobile Monday</a> we attended the <a href="http://webmontag.de/doku.php?id=muenchen&DokuWiki=7cc4cb5a995f972dca7ec8295515104a">Webmontag in Munich</a>. Webmontag is a great platform to meet interesting people from the web business. Organized by <a href="https://www.xing.com/profile/Martin_Szugat">Martin Szugat</a> and taking place at the <a href="http://www.amiando.com/">amiando</a> office the event was quite the opposite from the Mobile Monday because of its very relaxed atmosphere and start-up minded people attending.<br></p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the beginning <a href="http://www.amiando.com/about.html">the guys from amiando</a> showed us their office and gave a little insight into their &ldquo;working culture&rdquo;. After that we (around 40 attendees) got a chance to chitchat and network. Food and drinks were available &ndash; thanks to amiando! Due to the laid-back atmosphere it was pretty easy to get in touch with a lot of new people.<br></p>

<br>


<p>After an hour of networking and before Felix Haas of amiando could begin with his presentation we started going around the room introducing ourselves one after the other by giving ourselves 3 tags each. The audience was pretty mixed: software &amp; web developers, startup entrpreneurs, marketing executives and also people from well-known companies such as the Boston Consulting Group, Süddeutsche Zeitung or Autoscout24.de &ndash; even a doctor joined this Webmontag :)<br>
After his introduction Felix got a chance to start with his presentation about <a href="http://www.amiando.com/">amiando</a>, a web service to invite people and send out customized invitations to your events. Talking about founding and funding the company as well as developing the platform amiando, he gave us some interesting insights and good advice.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Then Florian Steger of <a href="http://www.kupferwerk.com/de/">Kupferwerk</a> talked about Micro communities and how brands, media companies and organisations can enhance their customer life-cycle through online communities. It was also a very interesting presentation with quite interesting marketing insights on top.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The last presentation was held by our very own <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/about/rocco-georgi/">Rocco</a> about Mobile AJAX. Compared to the other presentations his was more technical-oriented, but still very interesting. There were a lot of questions about the mobile web in general and the use of AJAX on mobile devices. Unfortunately we ran out of time, so  <span class="urlextern">Martin had to postpone his presentation to next Webmontag.</span><br>
<span class="urlextern"> </span>After the three presentations we got another chance to network. Although it was planned to change the location and go to a pub, amiando offered us their office and even provided us with some free beer &ndash; very cool!<br></p>

<br>


<p>The event started at 7:00 pm and the last people left after 12 midnight.<br>
All in all it was a great evening, very social and a great opportunity to meet new and interesting people, to discuss business or technical related topics and to talk to start-ups and entrepreneurs like Johannes from <a href="http://kesto.org/">kesto.org</a> (<a href="http://kesto.org">web based password manager</a>). Even if you look for a job in the IT business, it is a great opportunity to meet your new employer. Right now every company that presented is looking for new employees. So get in touch! Also refer to <a href="http://www.amiando.de/webmontag_muc?viewMode=photos&pictureCount=${pCount}">some pics of the evening</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<p>We also brought up the idea of doing a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pecha_Kucha">PechaKucha</a> (20 slides with 20 seconds each) session next time &ndash; just like <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/xml-2006-conference-boston-pecha-kucha-pechakucha_67.html">what we have done</a> at <a href="http://2006.xmlconference.org/pechakucha.html">last years XML conference in Boston</a>. It was a real blast there and maybe a perfect way to do presentations (or at least part of them) at such an evening, because of the limited time reserved for presentations. So we&rsquo;re encouraging everybody interested to respond!<br></p>

<br>


<p>We are really looking forward meeting more interesting people at the next Webmontag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Monday, Munich 02/05/2007]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-monday-munich-02052007_72.html"/>
    <updated>2007-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-monday-munich-02052007_72</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img style="float: right; width: 150px; margin-left: 5px" alt="MobileMonday" title="MobileMonday" src="http://www.mobilemonday.net/mm/img/logo_mm.gif" />We have been at this week&rsquo;s MobileMonday in Munich, Germany. Being the first &ldquo;real&rdquo; MobileMonday for us, except the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-20-event-in-san-francisco-well-be-there_58.html">Mobile 2.0 Event</a> in San Francisco last November, and being the first MobileMonday in Munich at all it has been a premiere in many ways. The overall topic of the evening was &ldquo;Next Generation Mobile Internet&rdquo; and it sounded like the perfect topic for PavingWays.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Here&rsquo;s a quick review of the event from our perspective.<br></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The event was organized by the MoMo Munich people, namely Daniel Melter, Harald Mueller and Christian Ehl. Russell Buckley was &ldquo;hired&rdquo; as the MC of the evening and he did a good job, especially with silencing the crowd at some points during the evening.<br></p>

<br>


<p>When we arrived at the location one thing was clear: this was no cheap location &ndash; situated in the heart of Munich, the &ldquo;8seasons&rdquo; is a premium-class party location right accross the opera house -very nice, except parking is not cheap anywhere around.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Speakers and presentations of the evening promised to be very interesting in the event schedule. Unfortunately most of the presentations turned out to be more product pitches than anything else. We would have preferred to hear more about general trends, applications and innovations and especially about the &ldquo;Next Generation Mobile Internet&rdquo; as it was advertised than we actually did. Here&rsquo;s the details&hellip;<br>
<strong>Speakers and Presentations</strong><br>
<strong>Teppo Paavola (<a href="http://www.nokia.com/">Nokia</a> RnD)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>His presentation start centered around convergence (mobileTV) and divergence (connection methods,users, devices). Then he explained the &ldquo;long tail&rdquo; (many smaller groups) and that non-voice applications on phones in general were in a very early stage.<br></p>

<br>


<p>New application approaches should be beta tested, intuitive, based on existing web techologies and on open platforms &ndash; nothing new, but amen to that. He went on examining what would be the most popular services in a world where everything is connected and concluded:<ul>  <li>friend networks</li>    <li>pictures and sound</li> <li>interactive stuff like translators</li></ul><br>
Again amen to that.<br>
One interesting part of the presentation was the fact that Teppo brought a <a href="http://www.nokia.com/A4136017?category=n95">Nokia N95</a>, we didn&rsquo;t manage to talk to him afterwards and see it though.<br>
<strong>Klaus Menhorn (<a href="http://www.mmetrics.com/">M:Metrics</a>)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Klaus presented his company and the services they are offering. Basically they track user behavior and device capabilities &ndash; I wanted to ask the question how deep this capability examination would go, i.e. if they could tell me if a given device&rsquo;s web browser suports the XMLHttpRequest or not, but I didn&rsquo;t manage to.<br></p>

<br>


<p>An interesting fact on his slides was that the market sizes of the US (200m) and the top 5 European countries (GB, IT, ES, D, F) was about equal.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Unfortunately there was nothing to see about mobile web usage whatsoever.<br>
<strong>Henning Ralf (<a href="http://www.iconmobile-group.com/index.php">iconmobile</a>)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>My favorite presentation of the evening, both because of its content and the way it was presented. The main topic was social networks and user generated content. The most interesting bits were:<ul>   <li>users of any service demand an ROI</li> <li>on a typical operator portal users mostly (24%) use messaging/chat and downloads (20%)</li> <li>revenues with social networks and blogs are soaring</li>    <li>walled gardens are mostly walled deserts</li>   <li>buddy lists are the center of social networks and very important</li>   <li>many accounts does not mean many users</li> <li>segmentation and a special purpose of a network are important</li>  <li>the trend in mobile businesses shifts from operator-user to operator-publisher-aggregator-advertiser-user models</li>   <li>other trends are: monetarization, mobilization, segmentation, vertical integration and community channel shift</li></ul><strong>Mikko Saarelainen (<a href="http://www.gofresh.de/">Gofresh</a>)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Mikko also did a good job presenting his service <a href="http://www.itsmy.com/">itsmy.com</a>, a social networking and content sharing application that is exclusively available on the mobile web. They launched in May 2006 and have currently more than 250.000 registered users with an esimated 4 million in the end of 2007. The service is completely free and revenue is generated from advertisement.<br></p>

<br>


<p>An interesting thing was that they review every content element that is being contributed by the community. There was also a statement that mobile web access in Germany is more expensive than anywhere else in Europe, whereas in some countries it&rsquo;s actually free.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Mikko also presented his predictions for the future:<ul>    <li>flatrates for mobile data transmissions will increase along with the user&rsquo;s acceptance</li> <li>mobile content and mobile phone optimized web sites will increase</li>  <li>mobile communities will be the ultimate CRM tool</li>   <li>by 2010 everyone will have a mobile phone with internet access and there will be more users using their phone to access the web than their computers</li></ul><strong>Bastian Lehmann (<a href="http://www.refreshmobile.com/about/refresh-mobile.htm">Refresh Mobile</a>)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Another product pitch &ndash; this time it was an installable application (Java) that connects to the web and pulls electronic versions of magazines for later viewing (offline). The application is called <a href="http://www.mobizines.com/">Mobizines</a> and the company is a management buy-out from T-Mobile.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The application is basically free, but every issue of one of the electronic magazines costs you a couple of cents (or pence). To me it appeared like you would get a nice looking RSS reader and pay for the content.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The mobile web was missing here entirely &ndash; except that the magazines are downloaded to your phone through a GPRS connection.<br>
<strong>Andy Smith (<a href="http://admob.com/">admob.com</a>)</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>And yet another product presentation &ndash; this time even related to the mobile web! admob.com made news recently for <a href="http://www.hot-moco.com/?p=103">serving one billion mobile ads</a>. Simply put they do affiliate programs, just not with banners, but text ads &ndash; and of course for mobile websites and services. The main emerging opportunities for selling text ads this way were interesting:<ul> <li>number of phones with browsers is increasing</li>   <li>there&rsquo;s a growth in off-portal mobile websites</li> <li>there are many new channels in general: mobile content, proucts and websites</li></ul><br>
To finish off, Andy presented a complete walk-through on admob.com &ndash; from creating a user account over creating a simple text ad to spending 10 bucks in 3 minutes. Very impressive, I just felt a little bad for the guys that actually clicked on these text ads with no real destination.<br>
<strong>People Met</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>There were a few possibilities to meet people during the whole event. The first one was while lining at the entrance. Then there was some socializing going on before and after the presentations. That&rsquo;s when we met one of the rather few attendees that was not working in a major mobile related company (carriers, advertising agencies, consulting etc.). We met one or two MobileMonday Munich people and people from Vodafone, Sevenone Interactive and a couple of other larger companies and had some interesting talks.<br>
I also had a little chat with <a href="http://www.bennolan.com/">Ben Nolan</a>, apart from being a RoR hacker and snowboarder he&rsquo;s trying to establish a <a href="http://mosoz.de/">mobile social network in Germany</a> quite soon.<br>
<strong>Lessons Learnt</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Many people at MobileMonday wear suites and are from big companies. We had expected to meet some more start-up people at these events, but apparently MoMo is a good reflection of what is going on in the mobile industry in general &ndash; big companies are big in business, but here and there smaller start-ups are coming in. We will continue to do so <strike>and will also attend the <a href="http://www.mobile-monday.de/web/guest/dusseldorf">next MobileMonday in Düsseldorf</a> in the end February</strike>.<br>
<strong>What Else</strong><br></p>

<br>


<p>Slides of all MobileMonday&rsquo;s presentations in Germany can be found <a href="http://www.mobile-monday.de/c/portal/layout?p_l_id=PUB.1.24">at the MobileMonday Germany website over here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
