<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mobile Trends | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/mobile-trends/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T21:56:03+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PavingWays Limited]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attend 3 Exciting Mobile Events on 1 Day!]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/attend-3-exciting-mobile-events-on-1-day_1872.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/attend-3-exciting-mobile-events-on-1-day_1872</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mark the date: <strong>15. November 2010</strong>! This Monday will be packed with <strong>3 exciting mobile events</strong> all taking place at the same location at <a href="http://maps.google.nl/maps?f=q&amp;q=Platz+der+Ideen%2C+40476+Düsseldorf">Grey&rsquo;s in Düsseldorf</a>:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Mobile Unconference</li>
    <li>Vodafone Developer Day</li>
    <li>MobileMonday</li>
</ol>


<p>This is a great opportunity to learn more about many mobile development topics and get in touch with mobile enthusiasts from all over the world. <strong>So join us for an exciting and informative day!</strong></p>

<p><strong>1. Mobile Unconference</strong></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.mobileunconference.com"><img class="size-full wp-image-1556 alignright" title="Mobile Unconference" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/mobunc_small1.png" alt="" width="292" height="133" /></a></strong></p>

<p>The day starts with the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-unconference-coming-to-germany_1489.html">Mobile Unconference</a>. Meet other developers, entrepreneurs, startups and technology companies to discuss the latest trends in mobile software. No frills, no strings attached, no
marketing-speak, only regular folks who make the mobile world more interesting every day. This is an UNconference and it&rsquo;s all about its participants &ndash; anybody can grab the microphone and talk about something interesting there!</p>

<p>Sign up here: <a href="http://www.mobileunconference.com"><a href="http://www.mobileunconference.com">http://www.mobileunconference.com</a></a></p>

<p><strong>2. Vodafone Developer Day</strong></p>

<p>Parallel to the Mobile Unconference and at the same location our developer friends over at <a href="http://developer.vodafone.com/">Vodafone</a> and <a href="http://www.appseleration.com/">Appseleration</a> organize a developer day covering the following topics:</p>

<ul>
    <li>Introduction to Vodafone developer</li>
    <li>Developing with JIL/WAC</li>
    <li>Cross Platform development and live demo</li>
    <li>Debugging tips and tricks with Ripple Emulator</li>
    <li>Testing on real devices with the Perfecto Mobile Cloud</li>
    <li>Bringing your apps to market</li>
</ul>


<div>More details here: <a href="http://vodafonedevdaysgermany.eventbrite.com/?ref=pavingways">http://vodafonedevdaysgermany.eventbrite.com</a></div>


<p><strong>3. MobileMonday</strong></p>

<p>The day ends with the Düsseldorf edition of MobileMonday. This time the topic will be <strong>Mobile Health</strong>. Learn more about the global mobile healthcare market and meet interesting people &ndash; networking till the ambulance arrives ;)</p>

<p>Find more details at the <a href="http://www.mobile-monday.de/events/mobile-health">MobileMonday Website</a> and please make sure you <strong>sign up there separately</strong>!</p>

<p><strong>Get ready for the mobilest day this year!
We hope to see you on Monday in Düsseldorf!</strong></p>

<p>PS: Please repost and <a href="http://twitter.com/pavingways/statuses/24962379968">retweet this!</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MWC News: Google's strategy and Android, Windows Marketplace ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mwc-news-googles-strategy-and-android-windows-marketplace_1565.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mwc-news-googles-strategy-and-android-windows-marketplace_1565</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some more interesting news announced at the Mobile Word Congress:</p>

<ul>
    <li><strong>Google's new strategy "Mobile First"</strong>
Google's new strategy: "Mobile First"  The company now focuses more on smartphones than on desktops. That means giving mobile top priority and launching new products first on mobile platforms before creating PC versions.

(Source: <a href="http://www.brighthand.com/default.asp?newsID=16235&amp;news=Google+Android+OS+CEO+Eric+Schmidt+Mobile+First">brighthand.com</a>)</li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li><strong>60,000 Android phone a day</strong>
Google's Android launched a year ago and is now available on <strong>26 different devices in 48 countries</strong>. <strong>60.000 Android devices</strong> running this operating systems are now <strong>being sold on a daily basis</strong>  meaning about<strong> 5.4 million</strong> handsets per quarter, or <strong>21 million</strong> per year. <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/smart-phone-sales-up-30-in-q4-2009_1174.html">Apple sold 8.7 million iPhones last quarter and 25 million in 2009</a>. Seems like Android is gaining ground, hopefully internal fragmentation will be taken care of (if that's possible).

(Source: <a href="http://blog.mobilegamesblog.com/2010/02/mwc-google-pleased-with-android-performance.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MobileGamesBlog+%28Mobile+Games+Blog.com%29">mobilegamesblog.com</a>)

<!--more--></li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li><strong>Windows Marketplace for Mobile has been updated</strong>
Windows Marketplace for Mobile, Microsoft's application store, has been updated. The biggest change is there will <strong>no</strong> longer be <strong>regional limitations</strong> on where apps are sold. This is great news for non-US customers because they could only see localized apps and the selection was very limited. Now thanks to the "geo selector" users can browse and purchase applications from different geographic catalogs / countries. The price of each app will show up in the <strong>user's local currency</strong>. Besides users can install downloaded apps onto their <strong>storage cards</strong>.

Developers also <strong>do not have to pay a US$10 fee </strong>for submitting their apps to additional markets anymore - only the US$ 99 submission fee has to be paid. <strong>VOIP apps</strong> will now be allowed unless a carrier specifically prohibits it. Microsoft now also opens its marketplace to <strong>Russia</strong>.

BTW Mobilegamesblog.com published some first screenshots of Windows Marketplace for the Windows Phone 7 Series devices. There is no real source named for these images, so they should be considered as a rumor: <a href="http://blog.mobilegamesblog.com/2010/02/first-screens-windows-phone-7-marketplace.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MobileGamesBlog+%28Mobile+Games+Blog.com%29">mobilegamesblog.com</a>

(Sources: <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/blog/main/archives/2010/02/windows_marketp_2.html;jsessionid=FQYMNXD2GEXUVQE1GHOSKHWATMY32JVN">informationweek.com</a>, <a href="http://www.theunwired.net/?item=mwc10-live-microsoft-updates-windows-marketplace-for-mobile-adds-features-and-enhancements&amp;5339">theunwired.net</a>)</li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li><strong>Alcatel unveils first Android phone</strong>
Handset maker Alcatel unveiled a number of new handsets at Mobile World Congress and interestingly its first Android-based phone OT-980. The phone will be available around June for less than 200 EUR in the UK, France, Spain and Italy. But they are still considering using other platforms, such as Windows Mobile, if prices come down.

(Sources: <a href="http://www.ciol.com/Technology/Mobility/News-Reports/Alcatel-jumps-on-Android-bandwagon/131717/0/">ciol.com</a>, <a href="http://www.totaltele.com/view.aspx?ID=453143">totaltele.com</a>)</li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li><strong>China Unicom and Huawei for low-cost smartphones</strong>
China Unicom plans to launch low-cost 3G smartphones - maybe in collaboration with Huawei which has also recognized that smartphones remain too expensive. Key to unlocking the potential usage of 3G is the need for a $150 smartphone with iPhone-like capabilities , said Guo Ping, CSO, Huawei Technologies and chairman of Huawei devices.

(Source: <a href="http://www.mobilebusinessbriefing.com/article/china-unicom-huawei-eye-low-cost-smartphones">mobilebusinessbriefing.com</a>)</li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li><strong>Deutsche Telekom: Open Apps Approach</strong>
Deutsche Telekom plans to further integrate with mobile apps and content stores. By partnering with leading applications stores Deutsche Telekom wants to offer its customers a T-Mobile dedicated channel with specific recommendations and the opportunity for mobile phone billing (instead of credit card payment).
Deutsche Telekom's open mobile internet strategy implies that customers ultimately get access to a wide choice of all available applications, regardless of their mobile phone brand. As a basis we provide easy log-in, registration, and payment processes, as well as Deutsche Telekom channels in existing stores and customer oriented recommendations," states Rainer Deutschmann, Senior Vice President Mobile Products.

(Source: <a href="http://finchannel.com/Main_News/Tech/58408_Deutsche_Telekom_drives_open_approach_to_apps_and_content_stores/">finchannel.com</a>)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Even More Mobile Applications Hit Cars]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/even-more-mobile-applications-hit-cars-2_1514.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/even-more-mobile-applications-hit-cars-2_1514</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/autolinq1.png"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1164" style="margin: 1px 5px;" title="autolinq" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/autolinq1.png" alt="" width="212" height="133" /></a>Last year in October I wrote in a <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-applications-hit-cars_1031.html">blog post</a> about smart phone applications coming to cars. Today I read an article about <a href="http://www.telekom.com/">Deutsche Telekom</a> and tyre maker <a href="http://www.conti-online.com/">Continental</a> joining this market as well.</p>

<p>They plan to put apps into all vehicles via an Android-based on-board computer. The prototype called <a href="http://www.autolinq.de/"><strong>AutoLinQ</strong></a> will be demonstrated at this year&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.cebit.de/homepage_e">Cebit show</a>. Inspired by the iPhone drivers can search for apps, download music, pick up news, check emails and answer them by using voice recording technology. The promise is: <strong>all without taking hands off the wheel or eyes off the road!</strong></p>

<p>Deutsche Telekom said in a statement that the core functions of AutoLinQ include an online address book linked to the navigation system. Drivers can type in journey destinations on the computer at home or work before getting in the car, or via their mobile phone when out and about. As the vehicle is connected to Deutsche Telekom&rsquo;s mobile network, drivers can call up information that tells them where the car is parked, or check whether the sunroof is open and close it remotely using their phone.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>According to the website of AutoLinQ, Continental plans to work with Android developers and automakers to certify a core set of applications. An <strong>AutoLinQ SDK</strong> is scheduled to be released already <strong>by the end of the first quarter this year</strong> &ndash; probably due to its closeness to the regular Android SDK.</p>

<p>In the <strong>second half of 2010</strong> Continental plans to demonstrate first applications and of course the new app store to automotive customers (yes another app store&hellip;).<strong></strong></p>

<p><strong>Sources:</strong>
<a href="http://www.autolinq.de/">AutoLinQ</a>
<a href="http://www.conti-online.com/generator/www/de/en/continental/automotive/themes/passenger_cars/interior/connectivity/autolinq/pi_autolinq_en.html">AutoLinQ</a> (Continental Website)
<a href="http://www.computerweekly.com/Articles/2010/02/01/240139/deutsche-telekom-picks-android-for-in-car-apps.htm">computerweekly.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Applications on TVs now and tomorrow and the day after]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-applications-on-tvs_1252.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-applications-on-tvs_1252</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After mobile phones and <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-applications-hit-cars_1031.html">cars</a> we now will be able to access our mobile apps on TV &ndash; This really is exciting <a href="news:">news:</a></p>

<p>At CES 2010 in Las Vegas Samsung announced the upcoming availability of of free and paid apps in <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-widget-wiki/manufacturer-driven-application-stores">Samsung&rsquo;s Apps store</a>, including apps for <strong>Televisions</strong>, <strong>Blu-Ray Players</strong>, <strong>Home Theater</strong> and <strong>Mobile Phones</strong>. The <a href="http://tv.samsungapps.com/">download service for TVs</a> will be available in July 2010.</p>

<p>I found two interesting videos from Samsung&rsquo;s press conferences:</p>

<object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="420" height="315" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/yH8nQHN_3dE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/yH8nQHN_3dE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object>




<object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="420" height="315" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/hB1Q2eiSpAQ&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/hB1Q2eiSpAQ&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object>


<p>I guess other manufacturer will enter the market pretty soon, too. It seems the web is getting more and more ubiquitous…<a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-widgets-the-ubiquitous-mobile-web_84.html">again</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Sources:</strong>
<a href="http://tv.samsungapps.com/">tv.samsungapps.com</a>
<a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology/2010/01/07/samsung-apps-tv-and-mobile-app-store-launched-115875-21948229/">www.mirror.co.uk</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Applications hit Cars]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-applications-hit-cars_1031.html"/>
    <updated>2009-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-applications-hit-cars_1031</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the <a href="http://www.iaa.de/">IAA in Frankfurt</a> (Frankfurt Motor Show) in September 2009 <a href="http://www.bmw.com/com/en/index.html">BMW</a>, <a href="http://www.nokia.com/">Nokia</a> and <a href="http://www.parrot.com/usa/">Parrot SA</a> unveiled plans for bringing smart phone applications to cars.</p>

<p>&ldquo;For software developers, this opens a whole new domain to sell their apps. For car makers, apps provide new ways to deliver infotainment and telematics services to customers. For motorists, apps allow them to enjoy their infotainment systems to the fullest, while paying only for the applications they want, thus saving them money. With apps so critical to the automotive market, companies are pushing approaches that benefit their specific goals. While the solutions shown at IAA were only concepts, they clearly reflect what will soon be on the market.&rdquo; said Kevin Hamlin, analyst for automotive electronics at <a href="http://www.isuppli.com/Pages/home.aspx">iSuppli Corp</a>.</p>

<p>Sounds good? Yes. Where&rsquo;s the catch? Doing it right!</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>BMW and its Concept BMW Application Store:</strong></p>

<p>BMW is the first car maker who is opening its own app store: the <a href="http://www.lifepr.de/pressemeldungen/bmw-group/boxid-121889.html"><strong>Concept BMW Application Store</strong></a>. The store offers several different apps and users can download them to their iDrive either directly in their car or via home PC (and then transfer the apps to the car system). The selection of apps ranges from the obvious Facebook, Xing and Twitter to podcasts, web radio, Geowiki, multimedia travel guides as well as various games. I am not sure how big the applications offering is in it&rsquo;s entirety, but it is a nice step in customizing your car to your needs. Another feature &ndash; maybe more useful than the rest and especially for business customers &ndash; is the ability to transfer contact data (addresses or phone numbers) to the navigation system or mobile phone connected to the car system.</p>

<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.bmwblog.com/2009/09/14/concept-bmw-application-store-to-be-introduced-at-frankfurt/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1042 aligncenter" title="infotaiment-1-655x245" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/infotaiment-1-655x245.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="187" /></a></p>


<p>Locations is also an important part: the apps are able to pull vehicle-related information. BMW has shown apps that draw on information from the vehicle navigation system and even plans to link to other data such as acceleration or braking data. The car&rsquo;s position is also taken from the navigation system and, if the system is actively guiding the car to a destination, information about the destination time and location can be used.</p>

<p><strong>Nokia, Navteq and Magneti Marelli</strong><strong> developing smart car technology:</strong></p>

<p>Nokia, who bought map provider NAVTEQ back in 2007 for around 8 billion (yes, USD), is more looking into <strong>mobile device integration with the vehicle</strong> rather than introducing apps. During IAA in Frankfurt, Nokia, NAVTEQ, and <a href="http://www.magnetimarelli.com/index.htm">Magneti Marelli</a> (automotive systems and components specialist) demonstrated a technology which seamlessly integrates smart phones into an in-vehicle infotainment system. Once connected, smart phone features, services and applications can be unlocked and driven through the in-car screens and audio systems embedded in the car. Users would be familiar with the user interface as it would be the same one they see on their smart phones. Through this connectivity, key data such as fuel levels (where is the next gas station), engine status, eco-friendly driving as well as location-based services (coupon for a coffee at a nearby gas station) can be extracted. ADAS (Advanced Driver Assistance System) -based safety features could also be included. For example to warn drivers to slow down for a sharp bend ahead.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are happy to be part of this new innovation and looking forward to the new opportunities this technology can bring,&rdquo; said Vesa Luiro, head of navigation development, Nokia. &ldquo;The infotainment system of a modern car is a natural extension for the capabilities of smartphones. Not only will it simplify the use of turn-by-turn voice guidance from <a href="http://maps.ovi.com/">Ovi Maps</a>, but also provide a new and easy way of accessing other content on the smartphone, such as music and delivering automotive specific widgets from the <a href="http://store.ovi.com/">OVI Store</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Connection from the mobile device to the infotainment system is made either via Bluetooth or USB cable. This technology known as &ldquo;<strong>Virtual Networking Computer layer</strong>&rdquo; is in alpha phase and was developed in collaboration with Nokia Research Center, Palo Alto.</p>

<p><strong>Parrot goes open source:</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.parrot.com">Parrot</a>, a wireless equipment supplier, unveiled an Android-based device (a head unit) that offers automotive implementation of all smartphone features. Great news for Android developers, who do not have to develop on a separate platform for cars. And this also means hundreds of apps are already available.</p>

<p>The head unit itself includes hands-free Bluetooth, A2DP audio streaming, speaker-independent voice recognition, multimedia connectivity, smart track browsing and playlist management, 3G+ Web browsing and 3.0 Wi-Fi and Bluetooth. Also check out Parrot&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Parrot/49623718343">Facebook</a> page and <a href="http://twitter.com/Parrot">Twitter Feed</a>.</p>

<p><strong>App store battle has started &ndash; who will win?
</strong></p>

<p>As you can see in <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-widget-wiki/app-store-overview">our Widget and App Store Wiki</a>, a lot of phone manufacturers and operators have already joined the mobile applications battle or are planning their move in this direction. It becomes clear that many other industries such as the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/review-frankfurt-book-fair-opportunities-for-publishers-retailers_993.html">book publishers</a> or car manufacturers are trying to get a piece of this cake. I totally agree with <a href="http://gigaom.com/2009/10/12/automotive-market-to-fuel-apps-and-app-stores/">gigaom</a> that the key to success in this app store battle will be <strong>interoperability</strong>. That&rsquo;s why I think Nokia and Parrot have a the better approach here and BMW&rsquo;s is a bit short-sighted with their proprietary and apparently closed system.</p>

<p>Users want a wide and ubiquitous selection of apps, preferably not bound to a special platform or device. There is more than enough fragmentation developers have to cope with in this area &ndash; screen sizes, device capabilities and on goes the list. <strong>If platform vendors want to attract developers to develop applications for their systems and devices they are best off supporting standards, preferably open ones and they need to take care of them by offering development tools and support in selling the applications in their app stores.</strong></p>

<p>We will soon see which car manufacturers do this right and which model will prevail.</p>

<p><strong>Sources:</strong><a href="http://www.bmwblog.com/2009/09/14/concept-bmw-application-store-to-be-introduced-at-frankfurt/">
cellular-news.com
bmwBlog.com</a><a href="http://www.mobile-ent.biz/news/34677/BMW-unveils-in-car-app-store">
mobile-ent.biz</a>
<a href="http://www.eetasia.com/ART_8800586838_499488_NT_00175140.HTM">eetasia.com</a>
<a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/pressRelease/idUS108979+15-Sep-2009+PRN20090915">reuters.com</a>
<a href="http://gigaom.com/2009/10/12/automotive-market-to-fuel-apps-and-app-stores/">gigaom.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
