<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Groupile | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/groupile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-06T12:47:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PavingWays Limited]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chairing Mobile Internet Conference in Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-internet-conference-in-berlin_174.html"/>
    <updated>2008-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-internet-conference-in-berlin_174</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iir-events.com/IIR-conf/Telecoms/EventView.aspx?EventID=1366"><img src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/mobile_internet_berlin.jpg" alt="Mobile Internet Berlin 2008" style="float: right; width: 150px; margin-left: 5px" /></a>We&rsquo;ll be going to Berlin on Sunday to attend the <a href="http://www.iir-events.com/IIR-conf/Telecoms/EventView.aspx?EventID=1366">Mobile Internet Conference</a>. The event is organized by <a href="http://www.iir-events.com">IIR Telecoms</a> and they asked me to chair the sessions on Monday 03/31/2008.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The topic for my introduction for that day is &lsquo;Mobile Web 2.0&rsquo;. I&rsquo;ll start learning all the buzz words of the past 3 years by heart over the weekend to be prepared ;)<br></p>

<br>


<p>Maybe I can slip in a little announcement concerning the long awaited launch of the<a href="http://groupile.com/"> Groupile Beta</a> that&rsquo;s due in April. We have about 140 people waiting, they signed up without really knowing what to expect, some of them are waiting since last year. April will clear things up.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The conference is gonna be a big opportunity to network and get in touch with many great people in the mobile and mobile web area. The speaker roster looks great even though <a href="http://www.ctiawireless.com/events/event_details.cfm?calID=670">CTIA/IEEE WCNC 2008 in Las Vegas</a> is at the same time. On Monday the following companies will be presenting and hold a roundtable discussion at the end of the day:<ul>   <li><a href="http://www.youtube.com">Google YouTube</a></li>    <li><a href="http://www.bluenove.fr/">Bluenove/Orange</a></li>  <li><a href="http://trutap.com/">trutap</a></li>    <li><a href="http://us.cyworld.com/">Cyworld</a></li>   <li><a href="http://www.itsmy.com/itsmy/">itsmy.com</a></li>    <li><a href="http://www.yahoo.com">Yahoo!</a></li>  <li><a href="http://www.emap.com">emap</a></li> <li><a href="http://www.zed.com">Zed</a></li>   <li><a href="http://www.telecomitalia.com">Telecom Italia</a></li>  <li><a href="http://www.eyeka.com/">Eyeka</a></li>  <li><a href="http://www.blinkbox.com/">blinkBox</a></li></ul><br>
The W3C, Jamba and many international carriers will also be there and present throughout the conference.<br></p>

<br>


<p>We&rsquo;re looking forward to meet you there, too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presenting Groupile at the FMC Summit in Munich]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/presenting-groupile-at-the-fmc-summit-in-munich_172.html"/>
    <updated>2008-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/presenting-groupile-at-the-fmc-summit-in-munich_172</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were invited to speak at <a href="http://www.iir-events.com/IIR-conf/Telecoms/EventView.aspx?EventID=1418">this year&rsquo;s FMC Summit</a> on rather short notice about three weeks ago. The event was organized by <a href="http://www.iir-events.com/IIR-conf/Default.aspx">IIR Telecoms &amp; Technology</a> and took place in Munich from 03/11/08 to 03/14/08. We had a chance to present <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/">PavingWays</a> and <a href="http://groupile.com/">Groupile</a> in the first of two &ldquo;Innovation Showcase&rdquo; sessions on Wednesday. It was a nice opportunity to present what we are working on to a critical and at least in part mobile-web-oriented audience.<br></p>

<br>


<p>To be honest we didn&rsquo;t really know what <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_Multimedia_Subsystem#Fixed.2FMobile_Convergence">FMC</a> was before the conference, but since it apparently was a topic incorporating &ldquo;mobile&rdquo; and &ldquo;convergence&rdquo; we felt like it was a good fit for us. FMC, belonging to the wide field of IMS, actually encompasses a wide range of services and technologies, mostly related to network infrastructure and the bundling and the convergence of various products, such as mobile and fixed line tariffs or DSL, phone and TV bundles also known as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_play_(telecommunications)">Triple play</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<p>We met many interesting people from an incredible amount of different countries, such as Belgium, Croatia, the Czech Republic, Egypt, Finland, Turkey, the UK. Most of them were representatives of major mobile carriers/network operators. We also had interesting discussions with representatives of the <a href="http://www.wi-fi.org/">Wi-Fi Alliance</a> and the <a href="http://devicemanagementforum.org/">Device Management Forum</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Some interesting points and thoughts from the presentations at the conference:<br></p>

<br>


<ul>
<li>Question: Will cool and ubiquitous devices (GSM, WiFI, Homezone) be network operator independent? That means the user could then choose the cheapest or quickest connection on demand across providers.<br>
Answer (T-Mobile): Users would love it, because polls show they see their mobile handset as a friend, but the provider as the cleaning lady. Users also want a cheap handset, but T-Mobile don&rsquo;t think that this will be happening. On the contrary T-Mobile Germany has an exclusive partnerhsip with Apple and they think this will be the way to go in the future.<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li>T-Mobile is relaxed about VoIP coming to the iPhone, because you can already make phone calls with it as opposed to a laptop where VoIP fills a gap.<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<ul>
<li>telephone numbers will become less relevant, sometime in the future it could be replaced by something like your Facebook or MySpace account<br></li>
</ul>


<br>


<p>Thanks go out to Alex from IIR Telecoms for the nicely organized and well managed event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy (belated) New Year!]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/happy-belated-new-year_154.html"/>
    <updated>2008-01-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/happy-belated-new-year_154</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the first post this year we wish all of you a happy and successful year 2008!<br></p>

<br>


<p>We have not blogged in a while. The good thing about this is that we were busy working on our first product, Groupile. <a title="Groupile Homepage" href="http://groupile.com">Groupile</a> will be a productive networking tool for groups. It is going to be ubiquitous, mobile-focused and web based. There will be a beta test soon, so make sure you sign up for that at <a title="Groupile Homepage" href="http://groupile.com">groupile.com</a>!<br></p>

<br>


<p>Another thing that we&rsquo;ve been working on was <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/products/frost-ajax-library">our Mobile Ajax Library, Frost</a>. We booked a domain for the project and installed a very basic homepage. <a title="Official Homepage of the Frost Mobile Ajax Library" href="http://frostlib.org"><a href="http://frostlib.org">http://frostlib.org</a></a> will from now on be the <a title="Official Homepage of the Frost Mobile Ajax Library" href="http://frostlib.org">official home of the Frost library</a> providing all the available information about the project. A pre-release version of the library is available for download there too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
