<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mobile Ajax | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/mobile-ajax/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T22:35:19+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attending Nokia Developer Summit 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/attending-nokia-developer-summit-2009_293.html"/>
    <updated>2009-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/attending-nokia-developer-summit-2009_293</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ll be going to Monaco by the end of April to attend the <a href="http://www.developersummit2009.com/"><strong>Nokia Developer Summit 2009</strong></a>.<a href="http://2009.nseries.com/specs.aspx"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-295" title="nokia_n97" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/nokia_n971.jpg" alt="" width="207" height="157" /></a><br></p>

<br>


<p>During this summit <strong>in Monte Carlo on 28-29 April</strong>, Nokia is holding a <a href="http://2009.nseries.com/competition/about.aspx">&ldquo;<strong>N97 24-hour Hackathon</strong>&rdquo; competition</a>. I am one of 10 developers selected by <a href="http://www.forum.nokia.com/">Forum Nokia</a> who is gonna hack together a Web Runtime (WRT) widget for the home screen of the <a href="http://2009.nseries.com/specs.aspx">new Nokia N97</a>.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The Hackathon session will be streamed live and I will be in action 24h competing face-to-face with the other developers. At the end of this Hackathon, <a href="http://2009.nseries.com/competition/top-10.aspx">all widgets</a> will be judged by a panel of experts from Nokia Forum &amp; Nokia&rsquo;s N97 team. The winning designer will get a Nokia N97 pre-loaded with the app. Also, the next to cash prizes, &ldquo;[&hellip;]The winning widget will also be awarded premium spotlight status on the main page of the new Nokia Ovi Store, which is opening in May. It will be free to download in Australia, Germany, Italy, Ireland, Russia, Singapore, Spain, United Kingdom, and United States. The apps which come second and third at the Hackathon judging panel will also get spotlight placement on the sight.[&hellip;]&rdquo; (Source: <a href="http://2009.nseries.com/competition/about.aspx">Nokia</a>).<br></p>

<br>


<p>Nokia is going through quite some replacements on the widget and content distribution front these days: Their WRT Widgets will replace formerly well received WidSets and maybe other apps too, and Nokia&rsquo;s new <a href="http://www.ovi.com/services/">Ovi store</a> will replace their current offering called Mosh.<br></p>

<br>


<p>I am really looking forward to the event &ndash; not just because I can spend some exciting days in Monte Carlo :), but also because it&rsquo;s a great opportunity to get in touch with many people in the mobile and mobile web area since a long time.<br>
<strong>Sources:</strong><br>
<a href="http://www.developersummit2009.com/">Nokia Developer Summit 2009</a><a href="http://2009.nseries.com/competition/about.aspx"><br>
Nokia N97 Widget Competition</a><a href="http://www.forum.nokia.com/"></a><a href="http://2009.nseries.com/specs.aspx">Nokia N97 Data Sheet</a><a href="http://www.forum.nokia.com/"><br>
Forum Nokia</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BlackBerry Browser Can Accesses GPS Location]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/blackberry-browser-can-accesses-gps-location_192.html"/>
    <updated>2008-07-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/blackberry-browser-can-accesses-gps-location_192</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve been monitoring the mobile browser market pretty closely during the last couple of years, especially in regard to Mobile Ajax and how it could help to create new and powerful web applications for mobile phones.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Mobile Ajax is a lot of things and it always depends on the individual&rsquo;s definition what is really meant, but one thing that is a pretty common aspect of Mobile Ajax is the ability that it might at some point be used as a gateway or API to connect the web browser on the phone with the device hardware, such as the GPS system thereby giving access to the device&rsquo;s position within a mobile web application.<br></p>

<br>


<p>These things are in development at every mobile browser vendor today, that much is for sure, but what&rsquo;s more interesting, because it&rsquo;s hardly known, is that <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold">this functionality already exists</span> on some BlackBerry Devices, namely those of the <a href="http://www.tonybunce.com/default.aspx">8800 series</a>! Now maybe we&rsquo;ve been too busy developing  <a href="http://groupile.com">our stuff</a> lately to notice, maybe this time nobody really made a big buzz out of this, but personally I feel bad that I missed this until now, because I feel this might have a tremendous impact on mobile web application development:<br></p>

<!--more-->


<p>As TonyB writes in an article called &ldquo;<a href="http://www.tonybunce.com/2008/05/08/BlackberryBrowserAmpGPS.aspx">Blackberry Browser &amp; GPS</a>&rdquo; on  <a href="http://www.tonybunce.com/default.aspx">his blog</a>, certain BlackBerries provide a JavaScript object within the web browser that allows the web application to access  latitude and  longitude from the GPS module on the phone. Security is taken care of by asking the user to allow (or not) the application access to the physical location of the device in a Yes/No alert() window. Simple and, if it works, tremendously powerful!<br></p>

<br>


<p>Too bad BlackBerry devices are known for not having the world&rsquo;s best web browser on them (to put it politely) &ndash; developer documentation seems not to be of much help either. But as r<a href="http://pwmwa.com/frost/results.php">esults from our ever-running Frost library test</a> show, there might be a BlackBerry device, the BlackBerry 8200  Cingular US (VendorID = 102), that already features support for Ajax. This could be a faked user agent string though, so if you have a 8820 and want to test it, just go to  <a href="http://pwmwa.com/frost/"><a href="http://pwmwa.com/frost">http://pwmwa.com/frost</a></a> &ndash; or we can test it ourselves as soon as you send us over a BlackBerry 8200 ;) As we develop <a href="http://groupile.com">Groupile</a>, we will make sure to include this as soon as possible too.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Please read <a href="http://www.tonybunce.com/2008/05/08/BlackberryBrowserAmpGPS.aspx">all details and the code listing in TonyB&rsquo;s article</a> &ndash; thanks for blogging about this!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Article on dev.opera.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/article-on-devoperacom_155.html"/>
    <updated>2008-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/article-on-devoperacom_155</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently wrote an <a href="http://dev.opera.com/articles/view/mobile-ajax-and-the-frost-ajax-library/">article for dev.opera.com</a> about Mobile Ajax and how the Frost Library can deal with that. There is a lot of introductory stuff in there and it might will be the longest and most comprehensive article I have been writing on the topic, there&rsquo;s even code snippets in there. So it might be a good read for anybody interested in the topic of Mobile Ajax.Thanks to David and Chris from Opera for making that happen and giving me the opportunity.You can read the <a href="http://dev.opera.com/articles/view/mobile-ajax-and-the-frost-ajax-library/">article at dev.opera.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Ajax Wokshop Mountain View 09/28/2007]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-ajax-wokshop-mountain-view-09282007_144.html"/>
    <updated>2007-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mobile-ajax-wokshop-mountain-view-09282007_144</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was attending the <a HREF="http://www.w3.org/2007/09/28-mobile-ajax-minutes.html">Mobile Ajax Workshop</a> at the Microsoft Campus in Mountain View. The whole workshop was very interesting and I met many interesting people from Japan, Korea, USA, UK, India and companies such as <a HREF="http://www.nttdocomo.com/">NTT DoCoMo</a>, <a HREF="http://nhncorp.com/">NHN</a>, <a HREF="http://vodafon.co.uk/">Vodfone</a>, <a HREF="http://www.aplixcorp.com/en/index.html">Aplix</a>, <a HREF="http://www.motorola.com/">Motorola</a>, <a HREF="http://www.sitepen.com/">SitePen</a>, <a HREF="http://nec.com/">NEC</a> and many more.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The event, being a workshop not a conference, was structured a bit different from what I experienced until now. There were different moderated discussions around topics related to Mobile Ajax.   These discussions were conducted in the form of panel discussions, where up to 4 panelists came up on &ldquo;stage&rdquo; and held a 5-minute introduction about their <a HREF="http://www.w3.org/2007/06/mobile-ajax/papers/">position papers</a> that were handed in before the event. I was up in a panel about &ldquo;one web&rdquo; with Alan from AOL, Dave from Google and Goro from DoCoMo. Honestly, it   felt a bit strange being in a panel with people from these major players, but it was cool and my presentation went ok too.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Some lessons learnt:<ul>    <li>AOL is using Mobile Ajax in their mobile search (works in IE) on <a HREF="http://wap.aol.com/search"><a href="http://wap.aol.com/search">http://wap.aol.com/search</a></a></li> <li>Aplix is working on a <a HREF="http://wiki.webvm.net/">Java based tool</a> that can provide access to device hard- and software to web aplications in the browser through a browser plugin, e.g. web app&lt;&ndash;&gt;browser&lt;&ndash;&gt;plugin&lt;&ndash;&gt;Java&lt;&ndash;&gt;GPS on phone</li>  <li>Japan is cHTML (iMode) all the way, but there are full web browsers too, many phones with 2 browsers</li>   <li>in Korea it&rsquo;s all XHTML (WAP2.0), many carriers develop their own Flash-like VMs to make content developers use their tools</li>    <li>Motorola will soon have a widget engine and Ajax support in their browser too</li>  <li>Content adaptors use many different ways to detect the user-agent, also, but not mainly <a HREF="http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/">WURFL</a>, more on <a HREF="http://www.w3.org/2005/MWI/DDWG/">DDGW</a></li> <li>Solutions for &ldquo;offline&rdquo; detection/browsing/management/handling are crucial, needed and <a HREF="http://gears.google.com/">Google Gears</a> looks promising</li></ul><br>
The <a HREF="http://www.w3.org/2007/09/28-mobile-ajax-minutes.html">minutes of the workshop</a> can be found <a HREF="http://www.w3.org/2007/09/28-mobile-ajax-minutes.html">through the W3C website</a>.  Here&rsquo;s the <a HREF="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/frost_mobile_ajax_workshop_2007.pdf" TITLE="Frost Ajax Library Slides">slides on the Frost Ajax Library</a> from my lightning presentation.<br></p>

<br>


<p>All in all it was a great day and I want to thank Microsoft for hosting the event and lunch, the W3C and the OpenAjax Alliance for putting this event together and especially Daniel Appelquist, Michael&trade; Smith and Jon Ferraiolo for their great work moderating and running the event. Looking forward to the next one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: "Bulletproof Ajax" by Jeremy Keith]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/book-bulletproof-ajax-by-jeremy-keith_135.html"/>
    <updated>2007-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/book-bulletproof-ajax-by-jeremy-keith_135</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bulletproofajax.com/"><img src="http://www.bulletproofajax.com/images/cover_small.gif" alt="image of book cover" style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right" /></a>I want to recommend a book by <a href="http://adactio.com/">Jeremy Keith</a>, called &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321472667/wohnflydasreg-21/">Bulletproof Ajax</a>&rdquo;. I recommend it for several reasons. First of all, the book is an excellent introduction to Ajax programming in general and everybody starting to write JavaScript code to do Ajax should read it before touching any of the libraries out there.<br>
Secondly the book is especially suited to anybody who is interested in writing Ajax powered apps on mobile devices and constrained browsers. After all the book is all about making JavaScript code bulletproof and that&rsquo;s exactly what you need to do if you are facing browser constraints, flaky implementations of JavaScript engines and a hugely fragment environment overall.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Jeremy&rsquo;s book is suited for the beginner, but also for the seasoned developer, since it makes it clear what it all comes down to: writing clean code that gracefully degrades (Jeremy calls his method to do this <a href="http://domscripting.com/blog/display/41">Hijax</a>) if the application runs in a less-than-ideal environment. There are many best practices and useful code snippets contained and topics such as JSON, web services and accessibility.<br></p>

<br>


<p>The book is not entirely new but nevertheless a must-buy, it was published New Riders Press in February 2007 and I urge everybody interested in Ajax to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321472667/wohnflydasreg-21/">grab a copy, e.g. at Amazon</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
