<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mobile Applications | PavingWays]]></title>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/categories/mobile-applications/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-06T12:47:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://pavingways.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PavingWays Limited]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript User Group Frankfurt #1]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/javascript-user-group-frankfurt-1_2197.html"/>
    <updated>2011-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/javascript-user-group-frankfurt-1_2197</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>March 28th will see the 2nd JavaScript User Group meeting in Frankfurt (JSUGFRA). I will do a little talk about different SDKs that enable you to bring your JavaScript application to many different platforms and devices, not in the browser but as an (almost) native app.<br></p>

<br>


<p>iOS, Android, Nokia, BlackBerry, HP/Palm and even Samsung TVs will be covered. I&rsquo;ll try to do this as a hands-on demo actually putting a simple JS-powered app onto some devices/emulators.<br></p>

<br>


<p>Here&rsquo;s the flyer:<br>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2198" title="JSUG FFM" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/JSUG_1.png" alt="" width="448" height="670" /><br></p>

<br>


<p>It&rsquo;s #1 because it started with #0 I suppose&hellip;<br></p>

<br>


<p>Follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jsugfra">@jsugfra</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23jsugfra">#jsugfra</a> and find <a href="http://bit.ly/jsugfra_1">all details on Xing</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webinos: New Project to enable Cross-Platform Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/webinos-new-project-to-enable-cross-platform-apps_1822.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/webinos-new-project-to-enable-cross-platform-apps_1822</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.webinos.org"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1512" title="webinos logo" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/webinos1.png" alt="" width="150" height="48" /></a><a href="http://webinos.org/">Webinos</a></strong> is a pan-European initiative trying to build a &ldquo;<strong>Secure WebOS Application Delivery Environment</strong>&rdquo;. It aims to create an open source platform that will &ldquo;enable web applications and services to be used and shared consistently and securely over a broad spectrum of converged and connected devices, including mobile, PC, home media (TV) and in-car units&rdquo;.<br>
 <br>
The consortium is led by the <a href="http://www.fokus.fraunhofer.de/en/fokus/index.html">Frauenhofer Institute for Open Communication Systems</a> and has already <a href="http://webinos.org/members">22 partners</a> including W3C, Samsung, Sony Ericsson, Telefonica, docomo, Deutsche Telekom, BMW and the University of Oxford. It has received a €10m funding from the EU and will run over three years.<br>
 <strong>Will webinos solve the fragmentation problem?</strong><br>
 <br>
As many developers know there are a lot of different application platforms out there already (Android, iPhone, Symbian, Web &hellip; you name it). Fragmentation and porting applications are huge issues for developers and expensive in regards to development cost and time.<br>
 <br>
The new consortium wants to solve this problem by creating an open source, web-based platform that would allow the same application to run across a very wide variety of device types. The platform can be used on any handset regardless of the OEM or carrier. Basically a universal OS or runtime environment to write once, run anywhere.<br>
 <strong>A very ambitious goal! </strong>Especially considering that maximum compatibility usually comes in a <em>least common denominator</em> package.<br>
 <br>
For us this project first and foremost raises some questions:<ul>   <li>How do other projects like JIL/the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/the-holy-wholesale-applications-community-wac_1225.html"><strong>Wholesale Applications Community</strong></a> (WAC) fit into the picture? They also aim to create open platforms for mobile apps and solve the fragmentation problem.</li>   <li>Is this gonna be a corporate-driven <a href="http://www.phonegap.com/">PhoneGap</a>?</li>   <li>Comparable to other approaches like <a href="http://www.mobileopenlaszlo.org">Mobile OpenLaszlo</a>?</li>   <li>Will HTML5 have a big part in this? (probably it will)</li> <li>How small will the least common denominator really be?</li> <li>No matter how web-based you are you need to deal with browser issues and fragmentation &ndash; how is this solved?</li>   <li>Are there too many cooks in the kitchen?</li>   <li>Where do Google, Apple and Nokia (and many others) fit into this?</li>  <li>Where are the developers? It is a tough task to convince developers to develop for your platform, no matter how great it might be. Other companies are already spending millions on this (some more successful than others).</li>   <li>Is someone of webinos going to present the project at the <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/mobile-unconference-coming-to-germany_1489.html">Mobile Unconference in November</a>?</li></ul><strong>What we think:</strong><br>
 <br>
A well funded project with a noble goal. Lots of players involved, many obstacles to take, many people to convince. The goal is very, very ambitious and the resulting platform will depend on making compromises. The Web is the platform of the future &ndash; this is another proof.<br>
 <strong>Sources and References:</strong><br>
 <a href="http://webinos.org/">webinos.org</a><a href="http://www.wholesaleappcommunity.com/">wholesaleappcommunity.com</a><a href="http://www.geek.com/articles/mobile/webinos-aims-for-one-app-to-work-on-all-mobile-devices-20100923/">geek.com</a><a href="http://www.heise.de/developer/meldung/Webinos-Neues-Konsortium-fuer-geraeteuebergreifende-Anwendungsplattform-1095060.html">heise.de</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baby Roulette now in App Store - some insights...]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/baby-roulette-now-available-app-store_1597.html"/>
    <updated>2010-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/baby-roulette-now-available-app-store_1597</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bit.ly/babyroulette"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1262 alignleft" style="margin: 1px 5px;" title="ladebildschirm" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/ladebildschirm-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a> Today our <strong>first iPhone game</strong> called &ldquo;<strong><a href="http://www.pavingways.com/games/babyroulette/">Baby Roulette</a></strong>&rdquo; was <a href="http://bit.ly/babyroulette">published on the Apple App Store</a>. The whole submission process was really fast. We submitted our app to Apple on Sunday afternoon, it went into review on Monday noon and today (Wednesday) morning it was published on the iTunes Application Store.<br>
 <br>
The game is very very simple, so maybe that&rsquo;s one of the factors for a speedy release&hellip;<br>
 <strong>Why did we build an app like this?</strong><br>
 <br>
Baby Roulette is a really simple and fun game for kids (mostly) to learn animal sounds. Our main intention for building this game is to get a simple and nice looking game quickly in as many App Stores as possible starting with Apple. Our next targets will be the <a href="http://store.ovi.com/">Ovi Store</a> , <a href="http://www.android.com/market/">Android Market</a> and <a href="http://www.vodafone360.com/en/web/home/index">Vodafone 360</a>, which is still running the &ldquo;<a href="http://widget.developer.vodafone.com/appstar">Vodafone 360 App Star Competition</a>&rdquo;.<br>
 <br>
We mainly want to gain insights about different application stores regarding users, downloads, major downloading countries, devices and of course we want to practically go through the whole process of building an application/game and releasing and actually selling it on different app stores. This will help us to enlighten our clients and of course we are also blogging about it. So here are some first facts&hellip;<br>
 <!--more--><br>
 <strong>What did we want to build?</strong><br>
 <br>
Our goal was to create a game or something to play with that would employ 2 major components for any game: animation and sound. We have a spinning arrow as an animation and we are playing sounds when the arrow spins and whenever the arrow stops (plays the animal&rsquo;s voice). The game concept itself has been around for ages of course, there are similar offers on the app store but it was simple enough to implement it quickly (a few days).<br>
 <br>
Another main goal was to go international &ndash; that&rsquo;s the reason we left out playing the typical, but localized &ldquo;The pig says&hellip;&rdquo; voice acting before the (international) animal sound. There is also no text except the title &ndash; however &ldquo;Baby&rdquo; and &ldquo;Roulette&rdquo; are both terms recognizable in a lot of languages even if they use a different alphabet.<br>
 <strong>How did we build it?</strong><br>
 <a href="http://phonegap.com/">Phonegap</a> &ndash; make sure you know about this application framework! It enables developers to write their application using web technologies &ndash; namely HTML, CSS and JavaScript &ndash; and then wrap it into a native application. The cool thing is, phonegap targets not only the iPhone, but all other major platforms, such as Android or BlackBerry and it provides access to device functionalities, such as the accelerometer or GPS location by extending the JavaScript API.<br>
 <br>
Originally the plan was not to use phonegap. The plan was to build a simple UIwebView application in Objective-C, the iPhone&rsquo;s native programming language.<strong> The main application would then also have been written in HTML/CSS and JavaScript</strong>. This is essential to us as we see ourselves as a mobile web development company, not as iPhone or Android developers. We strongly believe that creating native applications is just an <strong><a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/02/17/app-is-crap-why-apple-is-bad-for-your-health/">interim solution</a></strong> &ndash; the web will take over as the main application platform just as it did on the desktop. It&rsquo;s just a matter of time, <a href="http://www.whatwg.org/specs/web-apps/current-work/">HTML5</a> guys!<br>
 <br>
Unfortunately the mobile version of Safari does not play sound in the browser, but opens up the fullscreen audio player. The &lt;audio&gt; tag of HTML5 is also not available (yet), so no sound and we went with phonegap. This means carrying a little overhead, but also brings the advantage of simpler portability to other platforms and we are very happy with this decision.<br>
 <strong>Problems so far</strong><br>
 <br>
One major problem occurred as we were in the early stages of developing the web app: The spinning arrow used to be a &lt;canvas&gt; element that loads an image and is then rotated. As this rotation was scripted and angles were dynamically calculated, movement of the arrow was very smooth and without any obvious stepping. Also there was only one image &ndash; the arrow. Unfortunately this seems to result in heavy CPU load for anything below 3GS devices, so on an iPhone 3G the frame rate dropped notably.<br>
 <br>
Our solution was to go back to good old sprite animations. So now the arrow is just a &lt;div&gt; with a background sprite containing 60 versions of the arrow in 6 degree steps. The script now still calculates the current angle of the arrow as it spins, but now instead of rotating the image we are sliding the background image through the div so the matching version of the arrow is visible. This works, is fast enough on a 3G and it&rsquo;s a proven technology. Too bad there&rsquo;s no real HTML5 in there for now.<br>
 <strong>Next steps</strong><br>
 <br>
We&rsquo;ll release Baby Roulette for as many platforms as possible trying to keep porting efforts as low as possible and we&rsquo;ll surely gain many insights as we do this. We are also  already working on other games, of course. These will all be web based and cross-platform, but next time interaction and multi-player functionality will be our main topics. Maybe we will target grownups next time too :)<br>
 <br>
In the meantime we&rsquo;ll keep you up-to-date on porting to and releasing on different platforms and we hope you have fun playing <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/de/app/baby-roulette/id361958476?mt=8">Baby Roulette</a> with your kids or on your own!<br>
 <a href="http://bit.ly/babyroulette"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1268" title="Baby Roulette on the App Store" src="http://www.pavingways.com/wp-content/uploads/appstore_button1.png" alt="" width="140" height="47" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almighty "Wholesale Applications Community"?]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/the-holy-wholesale-applications-community-wac_1549.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/the-holy-wholesale-applications-community-wac_1549</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/8515813.stm">At MWC </a>a number of the world&rsquo;s leading telco companies including Vodafone, Orange, Samsung, Sony Ericsson, LG, Deutsche Telecom, SK Telecom, Verizon, AT&amp;T or China Mobile have announced the formation of an international alliance called &ldquo;<a href="http://www.wholesaleappcommunity.com/"><strong>Wholesale Applications Community</strong></a>&rdquo; (WAC) &ndash; to battle Apple.<br>
 <br>
They are aiming to build <strong>an open platform for mobile apps to all mobile phone users</strong> and want <strong>to solve the massive fragmentation problem</strong>.<br>
 <br>
They try to develop a common standard for applications within the next 12 months. The WAC is supposed to be a platform NOT an app store.<br>
 <br>
Of course, the app market is still a lucrative business and growing. Analysts at Gardner predict that the number of app downloads will rise to 4.5 billion (from 2.5 billion last year), yielding almost $30bn.<br>
 <br>
So far so good. But what does that mean, especially for us developers? Is this the right approach in the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Write_once,_run_anywhere">write once, run anywhere</a>&rdquo; direction?<br>
 <br>
The good thing is that the group intends to use existing open standards (JIL, BONDI, W3C) and that will make it a lot easier for developers creating apps across multiple platforms. Besides developers then have only one single gateway to access a vast potential and international customer base. It also saves a lot of time and resources. And the new alliance has access to more than three billion customers.<br>
 <br>
Well, does this sound too perfect to you? There are still a lot of questions and even doubts, right?<!--more--> Did they form this alliance just to beat Apple or do they really care about the developers? I mean in the end they are all competitors and every one wants a big &ndash; if not the biggest &ndash; part of the &ldquo;app market cake&rdquo;, right?<br>
 <br>
I also think it will be really hard to manage an organization of so many well-known and big companies. There will be many time-consuming processes to make even small decisions everybody is pleased with. We can see similar things going on at the W3C already.<br>
 <br>
Another important fact is that some platforms are already &ldquo;hopelessly fragmented&rdquo; as <a href="http://gigaom.com/2010/02/15/why-the-wac-is-whack/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+OmMalik+%28GigaOM%29">giagom</a> points out: Windows has <a href="http://jkontherun.com/2009/02/19/editorial-the-uphill-battle-microsoft-faces-with-windows-mobile/">struggled with the splintering of Windows Mobile</a> and Google is <a href="http://jkontherun.com/2009/10/15/businessweek-android-faces-danger-of-fragmentation/">suffering from the emergence of multiple versions of Android</a>.<br>
 <br>
Will the WAC succeed? I guess it is too early to answer this question, but for sure it will be very very difficult to reach their ambitious goals &ndash; if not impossible. The idea is good and the app market needs standardization, but there are a lot of obstacles to overcome. Probably too many for the big companies that are involved in this organization.<br>
 <br>
Maybe this kind of organization should be built by developers, not telcos who are mainly interested in selling not building apps. Even the Chamber of Industry and Commerce consists of handicraft businesses not of retailers. What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MWC News: Google's strategy and Android, Windows Marketplace ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://pavingways.github.io/mwc-news-googles-strategy-and-android-windows-marketplace_1565.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pavingways.github.io/mwc-news-googles-strategy-and-android-windows-marketplace_1565</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some more interesting news announced at the Mobile Word Congress:<ul>   <li><strong>Google&rsquo;s new strategy &ldquo;Mobile First&rdquo;</strong><br>
Google&rsquo;s new strategy: &ldquo;Mobile First&rdquo;  The company now focuses more on smartphones than on desktops. That means giving mobile top priority and launching new products first on mobile platforms before creating PC versions.<br>
 <br>
(Source: <a href="http://www.brighthand.com/default.asp?newsID=16235&amp;news=Google+Android+OS+CEO+Eric+Schmidt+Mobile+First">brighthand.com</a>)</li></ul><ul>    <li><strong>60,000 Android phone a day</strong><br>
Google&rsquo;s Android launched a year ago and is now available on <strong>26 different devices in 48 countries</strong>. <strong>60.000 Android devices</strong> running this operating systems are now <strong>being sold on a daily basis</strong>  meaning about<strong> 5.4 million</strong> handsets per quarter, or <strong>21 million</strong> per year. <a href="http://www.pavingways.com/smart-phone-sales-up-30-in-q4-2009_1174.html">Apple sold 8.7 million iPhones last quarter and 25 million in 2009</a>. Seems like Android is gaining ground, hopefully internal fragmentation will be taken care of (if that&rsquo;s possible).<br>
 <br>
(Source: <a href="http://blog.mobilegamesblog.com/2010/02/mwc-google-pleased-with-android-performance.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MobileGamesBlog+%28Mobile+Games+Blog.com%29">mobilegamesblog.com</a>)<br>
 <!--more--></li></ul><ul>  <li><strong>Windows Marketplace for Mobile has been updated</strong><br>
Windows Marketplace for Mobile, Microsoft&rsquo;s application store, has been updated. The biggest change is there will <strong>no</strong> longer be <strong>regional limitations</strong> on where apps are sold. This is great news for non-US customers because they could only see localized apps and the selection was very limited. Now thanks to the &ldquo;geo selector&rdquo; users can browse and purchase applications from different geographic catalogs / countries. The price of each app will show up in the <strong>user&rsquo;s local currency</strong>. Besides users can install downloaded apps onto their <strong>storage cards</strong>.<br>
 <br>
Developers also <strong>do not have to pay a US$10 fee </strong>for submitting their apps to additional markets anymore &ndash; only the US$ 99 submission fee has to be paid. <strong>VOIP apps</strong> will now be allowed unless a carrier specifically prohibits it. Microsoft now also opens its marketplace to <strong>Russia</strong>.<br>
 <br>
BTW Mobilegamesblog.com published some first screenshots of Windows Marketplace for the Windows Phone 7 Series devices. There is no real source named for these images, so they should be considered as a rumor: <a href="http://blog.mobilegamesblog.com/2010/02/first-screens-windows-phone-7-marketplace.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MobileGamesBlog+%28Mobile+Games+Blog.com%29">mobilegamesblog.com</a><br>
 <br>
(Sources: <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/blog/main/archives/2010/02/windows_marketp_2.html;jsessionid=FQYMNXD2GEXUVQE1GHOSKHWATMY32JVN">informationweek.com</a>, <a href="http://www.theunwired.net/?item=mwc10-live-microsoft-updates-windows-marketplace-for-mobile-adds-features-and-enhancements&amp;5339">theunwired.net</a>)</li></ul><ul>   <li><strong>Alcatel unveils first Android phone</strong><br>
Handset maker Alcatel unveiled a number of new handsets at Mobile World Congress and interestingly its first Android-based phone OT-980. The phone will be available around June for less than 200 EUR in the UK, France, Spain and Italy. But they are still considering using other platforms, such as Windows Mobile, if prices come down.<br>
 <br>
(Sources: <a href="http://www.ciol.com/Technology/Mobility/News-Reports/Alcatel-jumps-on-Android-bandwagon/131717/0/">ciol.com</a>, <a href="http://www.totaltele.com/view.aspx?ID=453143">totaltele.com</a>)</li></ul><ul> <li><strong>China Unicom and Huawei for low-cost smartphones</strong><br>
China Unicom plans to launch low-cost 3G smartphones &ndash; maybe in collaboration with Huawei which has also recognized that smartphones remain too expensive. Key to unlocking the potential usage of 3G is the need for a $150 smartphone with iPhone-like capabilities , said Guo Ping, CSO, Huawei Technologies and chairman of Huawei devices.<br>
 <br>
(Source: <a href="http://www.mobilebusinessbriefing.com/article/china-unicom-huawei-eye-low-cost-smartphones">mobilebusinessbriefing.com</a>)</li></ul><ul> <li><strong>Deutsche Telekom: Open Apps Approach</strong><br>
Deutsche Telekom plans to further integrate with mobile apps and content stores. By partnering with leading applications stores Deutsche Telekom wants to offer its customers a T-Mobile dedicated channel with specific recommendations and the opportunity for mobile phone billing (instead of credit card payment).<br>
Deutsche Telekom&rsquo;s open mobile internet strategy implies that customers ultimately get access to a wide choice of all available applications, regardless of their mobile phone brand. As a basis we provide easy log-in, registration, and payment processes, as well as Deutsche Telekom channels in existing stores and customer oriented recommendations,&ldquo; states Rainer Deutschmann, Senior Vice President Mobile Products.<br>
 <br>
(Source: <a href="http://finchannel.com/Main_News/Tech/58408_Deutsche_Telekom_drives_open_approach_to_apps_and_content_stores/">finchannel.com</a>)</li></ul></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
